[music]
Hi, I'm Eric Anderson. And I'm Ivy Zhuang. We are Software Engineers on the gRPC
team at Google
We work most on the Java implementation
of gRPC and Proxyless Service Mesh
as an overview, gRPC supports a variety
of languages and platforms with rich
features, making it perfect for
microservices and distributed
applications
gRPC stands for gRPC Remote Procedure
Call. It is a CNCF incubating project
which is the same open-source foundation
as Kubernetes. Fun fact, gRPC also stands
for our golden retriever mascot, pancakes
let me first walk you through a "hello
world" example in gRPC
this is the protobuf file that defines
the API of the service called Greeter
and the request and response message
data structures
for those of you who are new to protocol
buffers, it is an easy and efficient
mechanism to serialize structured data
so that it can be transmitted over wire
specifically, at compile time, the
protobuf generator generates code to
interface with language specific runtime
libraries and the serialization format
for the data that is written to the
network connection
next, you write your application class
based on the protobuf generated source
code that handles a gRPC request
as a demo service, here we attach "Hello"
string and echo the name field in the
request
then we write the code to start the
server application
the main class will start a gRPC server
that is listening on port 50051 for
client connection when it starts running
the last piece of code is the main class
on the client side. it sends a request
through a gRPC channel towards the gRPC
server that we just sprung up
it logs the response data
this concludes our mini demo. this demo
is simple. but this is exactly the same
predecessor library at Google that
supports extremely high qps at the 10 to
the 10th power
with that in mind, let's look at some of
the features of gRPC
gRPC is available in many languages
there's Go, Java, C++, Python, and
many more. gRPC can communicate across
languages with a service definition and
generated code, making the experience
natural in each language
it is also available on many platforms
whether running on Linux, Mac, Windows, or
on mobile devices running iOS and
Android. gRPC can communicate between
them all. you get to choose the language
and platforms for your system
gRPC is built on HTTP/2 which is an IETF
standard. that makes it compatible with
many load balancers and proxies.
HTTP/2 reduces the number of TCP
connections, is binary, it includes header
compression, all of which help make gRPC
high performance, reduce latency, and make
better use of resources
but gRPC also supports direct
client-side load balancing, so when
appropriate, it can run without the
proxies, reducing the number of
components to manage and increasing
performance
This applies even with service meshes. gRPC
has support to directly communicate with
centralized configurations service
discovery servers like Istio and Google
Cloud's Traffic Director that lets it
participate in a mesh without the
headache and cost of sidecar proxies
as you learn gRPC, you'll find it is
great for microservices. gRPC's support
for monitoring systems allows them to
alert when your system is unhealthy, and
tracing system support lets you
understand and debug your system as it
grows. tools like interceptors allow you
to share functionality across services
like authentication and logging
gRPC has more advanced features like
streaming, which allows multiple requests
and responses within an RPC
this allows structuring the RPC in a way
more performant for your application
the feature list goes on
gRPC has become very widely adopted
since its 1.0 release in 2016. it is run
at scale at numerous companies and is
continually tested, fuzzed, and
benchmarked to preserve its strong
stability
thank you for watching, I hope this helps
you get started or refreshed with gRPC
you can now check out these websites or
watch other videos in the playlist
thank you